So friends, if you have just bought an old car
or a bike or you are planning to
buy one someday, then
this video is perfect for you. In today's
video, we will learn
how to transfer your ownership in the insurance policy, that is, how to
change your name in the ownership rights and get it
updated in your policy.
Why is it necessary now? First of all, let us
discuss this. See, the insurance
policy is a level contract
between the owner of the RC and the insurance company, that is, the insurance company will
take the responsibility of only the liability of the
owner registered in the RC. As you get the
RC transferred when you buy an old vehicle,
it also becomes very important
that you go to the insurance company
and get your name updated in your insurance policy as well. Otherwise, the name
in the RC will be updated
but the ownership in the insurance policy will
remain in the name of the old owner, then
your nichal contract will become white, that is, it will
not be continued. So friends, what happens is that
as soon as you buy an old
vehicle, you get its RC transferred for yourself,
but you
only see its date in the insurance policy.  Let's assume
that it has not been done on one yet, now it will take some time for it to be done on gas and
you people do not get your ownership rights done in it, it is a
general process, that is why we believe
that if the insurance of the vehicle has come in 27 then the
vehicle is the same, so the insurance is of the
vehicle, but when you get the
ownership transferred in your RC, then it is
mandatory to get it transferred in the insurance policy also, otherwise you will not get the claim,
now friends, that is why we make videos on this channel,
information so that
you do
not suffer any major loss due to lack of even the smallest information, so friends, come and become a part of
our DSC Solutions family and
friends, if you have not subscribed to the channel yet, then
please subscribe to the channel
and by pressing the bell icon,
set the notifications to all so that no
important information is missed
and you do not suffer any loss, so
friends, in today's video we will know what
is the process of getting the ownership transferred,
which documents do you need in it
and after completion of this entire process,
what will be your total posting in it, let's watch the
video  Let's start, friends, first of all, let's
know what is the
process of transfer endorsement, its
process is quite simple, when your financial
vehicle is transferred in your name
or the RC of the bike, whatever you have
purchased in the middle, that ownership comes in your name,
after that you have to tell this thing either by
going to the office of the insurance company in which
you have followers of the insurance company or to
your insurance consultant or agent from
whom you have purchased the policy that brother, the
RC has been made in my name, now get the
thing updated in my policy as well that
I have got the insurance of that vehicle and if I do it
now, then I will be the claimant of it,
this liability will
cover my vehicle and the time taken for this,
friends, is of fourteen days, from the time of
making your RC to fourteen days, you have to
intimate this, but most of the time it happens
that it takes a
lot of time for the RC to come from the registration authority and even
after that, if you have to get the endorsement done, then there is
no need to worry, only one
step will increase in it that  Your vehicle
will be inspected in that case, that is,
they will verify the video or photo of your vehicle whether the
vehicle is in good condition or
not, after that they will do the enrollment for
transfer of ownership, so this process is just this much,
but in this you
also need some comments, now let's talk about which
documents are those, it is absolutely basic for 2 minutes, that is,
first of all
you need your real RC, which has been transferred in your name for
a vehicle, plus
you need the insurance policy which is in the
name of the old age, you should
take that policy with you, plus you need a
request letter along with this,
you will have to give the request letter to the insurance company
that I have purchased this vehicle and
my name should be updated in it, the RC has been
updated in my name and many
insurance companies
can also take a request letter in the name of salary, in which
they will say that I have sold out this vehicle, so
whatever your skills are,
this policy should be transferred in their name by changing your name, so
this is the basic in which the documents, when
you take it, the insurance
You go to the company or consultant for
its final party, how much will the total expense be
or not, what is the cost of this entire process,
but friends, the
fee decided by IRDA in this is
₹50 plus GST, which totals to only
₹10, that is, those rupees are just the basic
expenses, but many times
you have to pay additional money as well, how do you present it,
see what is there, if there is a
no claim bonus in your policy, that is,
they take some discount of no claim bonus from the policy in the name of the first owner, then
you will have to pay that amount
to the insurance company, its revision is that the
no claim bonus
remains with the owner of the vehicle, that is, the one who will remain with them while turning on the prevent,
you will not get that as well, but when you have become the
registered owner, then the timing of your NCP
slab will start now, so if you turn
on your NCP in the future, you will continue to get
your policy,
but send the complete NC of the old policy  If you had it in your policy,
you will have to surrender it
to the insurance company. But if there is no such bonus in your policy, then
now your expense is only
₹15 from them. To
know more about NCP, you
can watch the entire video by clicking on the i button.
I have explained in detail what the no claim
bonus is and how much you get
in which year. Friends, apart from this, there can be
expenses as well, which is for inspection
charges, that is, after Chola Din, if you
apply for an endorsement for infection, then the
insurance company
can also charge you for inspection. It depends on
which area you are in and how far this
patient had to travel or how far the visit
is from their infection branch. Friends, these are
its only expenses. So
friends, if you have watched the video till here
and you have understood how easy
its process is and how low its cost is, then
go and check now. Match your insurance
policy and registration certificate.
Match the RC to see if the
name is the same in both. If not, then please
Talk to your consultant about the insurance company and
get it updated so that none of your
claims are missed and if you are
unable to get any work done in any way then become a
part of the quality of DSE Solutions and hit the subscribe
button. See you in the next video. Take
care, stay fit and stay healthy. Thank you. Now do it.